1004 Occidental Dr. Redlands CA, 92374 909-637-6348

miketerry021@gmail.com

Web Portfolio - https://github.com/miketerry021.github.io LinkedIn Profile - https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-terry-36b467270/

MICHAEL TERRY

OBJECTIVE

I've earned my B.S. in Computer Science: Software Engineering over the course of 5 years, with the first 3 1/2 years at Mt. San Antonio Community College in Walnut, California, and the last 1 1/2 year at Southern New Hampshire University (SNHU). Throughout my time at both schools, I've developed various projects in different programming languages and databases which include C++, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, and MongoDB. These projects cover a range of software development skills and techniques which include, application design, algorithms and data structures, CRUD operations, utilizing secure coding techniques, unit testing, exception handling, input validation, and reverse engineering undocumented legacy code to recreate a new secure and applications. By collaborating with classmates and colleagues, these projects granted me experience with the different phases of the Software Development Lifecycle within an Agile-Scrum project management structure.

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

DEGREES

Southern New Hampshire University

B.S. Computer Science: Software Engineering

DESKTOP SUPPORT

CompTIA A+ Certification

CompTIA Network+ Certification

SKILLS Soft Skills

	Time Management	Communication
	Time Management	Communication
•	Customer Service	Documentation
•	Teamwork	Adaptability
•	Problem Solving	Leadership
•	Attention to Detail	Work Ethic
•	Agile-Scrum	

Technical Skills

•	C++	Java
•	HTML5	CSS

JavaScript C#

Android (Java Algorithms & Data Structures

MySQL MongoDB

OpenGL .NET Framework

Unit Testing
Reverse Engineering

WORK HISTORY

CS STUDENT, SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY & MT SAN ANTONIO COLLEGE, COMPUTER SCIENCE, GPA: 3.6

August 2019 - May 2024

- Developed and debugged projects is C++ while utilizing concepts such as: Arrays, Vectors, Abstraction, Polymorphism, Inheritance, Looping, Recursion, If Else Branches, Pointers, Containers.
- Developed and debugged projects in Java while utilizing concepts such as: Arrays, Abstraction, Polymorphism, Inheritance, Looping, Recursion, If Else Branches, Array Lists.
- Created web page projects with HTML5 and linked them with CCS and JavaScript files.
- Used MySQL to manage database projects by inserting, updating, and deleting database records, importing database files, and creating and altering Tables. Also queried records with Joins.
- Utilize Agile principles for project management while working in SCRUM teams.

HELPDESK SUPPORT SPECIALIST, SAN BERNARDINO COUNTY SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS, SAN BERNARDINO, CA

11/08/2021 - Current

- Install, maintain, configure, and update desktops, laptops, Chromebooks, iPad, and printers.
- Provide end users with hardware and software support.
- Deploy images to new desktops and laptops.
- Document and maintain asset inventory system.
- Performs maintenance on server and networking equipment.
- Organizing projects which include:
 - o Computer lab setups.
 - Implement technology initiatives from staff and administrators.
 - Practicing Agile principles
- Providing quotes for new products.
- Manage user accounts through Active Directory and Office 365

IS SYSTEMS SUPPORT TECHNICIAN, ONTARIO-MONTCLAIR SCHOOL DISTRICT, ONTARIO, CA

1/27/2014 - 10/27/2021

- Install, maintain, configure, and update desktops, laptops, Chromebooks, iPad, and printers.
- Provide end users with hardware and software support.
- Deploy images to new desktops and laptops.
- Document and maintain asset inventory system.
- Performs maintenance on server and networking equipment.
- Organizing projects which include:
 - o Computer lab setups.
 - Implement technology initiatives from staff and administrators.
 - o Practicing Agile principles
- Providing quotes for new products.
- Manage user accounts through Active Directory and Office 365

EDUCATION

MT. SAN ANTONIO COLLEGE, COMPUTER SCIENCE - TRANSFER, WALNUT CA, 2019 – 2021, GPA: 3.2

Completed General Education coursework and Computer Science coursework before transferring to the University level with a GPA of 3.2. Computer Science coursework includes programming languages C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY, B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE: SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, 2022 – 2024, GPA: 3.6

Current student, completing coursework to earn a B.S. in Computer Science. Computer coursework includes programming languages C++, JAVA, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

REFERENCES

MICHAEL HARTE

Client Systems Administrator, San Bernardino County Superintendent of Schools

909-252-5675

michael.harte@sbcss.net

RAY SANCHEZ

Systems Manager, San Bernardino County Superintendent of Schools 909-382-5676

ray.sanchez@sbcss.net

KYRIE LEWIS

Network Technician, San Bernardino County Superintendent of Schools 909-386-2734 kyrie.lewis@sbcss.net